Guide to the Morris Edward Opler papers, [ca. 1960-1996]
Opler, Morris Edward papers, [ca. 1960-1996]
- Series VIII. Additional Uncategorised Material
  - "Cause and Effect in Apachean Agriculture, Division of Labor, Residence Patterns, and Girls' Puberty Rites," American Anthropologist, 74, No.5, 1133-1146. 1972 (Box 124, Folder 18)
  - "Lipan Apache Navigation," The Masterkey, 49, No.2, 70-72. 1975 (Box 124, Folder 19)
  - Review article on The Jicarilla Apaches: A Study in Survival by Dolores A. Gunnerson, in Plains Anthropologist, 20, No.68, 150-157. Corrigenda are published in Plains Anthropologist, 20, No.70, 306. 1975 (Box 124, Folder 20)
  - "Applied Anthropology (University of Oklahoma), 16, No.2, 1-77. 1975 (Box 124, Folder 21)
  - Comment on "The Bow and the Hoe: Reflections on Hunters, Villagers, and Anthroplogists" by Sol Tax, Current Anthropology, 16, No.4, 531. (Issue in honor of Sol Tax) 1975 (Box 124, Folder 22)
  - "Doctrinal vs. Statistical Interpretations: An Examination of Apachean Endogamy," The Masterkey, 49, No.4, 139-146. 1975 (Box 124, Folder 23)
  - "Problems in Apachean Cultural History, with Special Reference to the Lipan Apache," Anthropological Quarterly, 48, No.3, 182-192. (Special issue, edited by Michael Kenny, in honor of Regina Flannery Herzfeld). 1975 (Box 124, Folder 24)
  - "The Indian Consolidation Policy and the Chiricahua Apache," Papers in Anthroplogy (University of Oklahoma), 17, No.1, 43-50. 1976 (Box 124, Folder 25)
  - "Harry Hoijer, 1904-1976: An Ethnologist's Appreciation," Papers in Anthropology (Univ. of Oklahoma), 17, No.2, 229-231. 1976 (Box 124, Folder 26)
  - "Addendum to the Obituary of John P. Gillin," American Anthropologist, 78, No.4, 896-897. 1976 (Box 124, Folder 27)
  - Comment on "Ancient Society and Morgan's Kinship Theory 100 Years After" by Raoul Makarius, Current Anthropology, 18, No.4, 720. 1977 (Box 124, Folder 28)
  - "Preface," in special issue on the Philippines, Papers in Anthropology (University of Oklahoma), 19, No.1, i. (Spring) [First of two volumes on the Philippines]. 1978 (Box 124, Folder 29)
  - "Preface," in special issue on the Philippines, Papers in Anthropology (University of Oklahoma), 19, No.2, i. [Second of two volumes on the Philippines] Fall, 1978 (Box 124, Folder 30)
  - "Marvin Kaufmann Opler, 1914-1981," American Anthropologist, 83, No.3, 617-621. 1981 (Box 124, Folder 31)
  - "Footnote to Woodbury's Letter," in the "Correspondence" section of Anthropology Newsletter, 28, No.1, 2. Jan., 1987 (Box 124, Folder 32)
  - "Response to Dr. Farrer," in the "Past Is Present" section ("Further Amplification on Apache Fieldwork and the Schmerler Death"), Anthropology Newsletter, 28, No.3, 3. March, 1987 (Box 124, Folder 33)
  - "Comment on 'Engineering Internment'," American Ethnologist, 14, No.2, 383. [Re article by Orin Starn on anthropologists and the War Relocation Authority] May, 1987 (Box 124, Folder 34)
  - "A Further Note about the 1931 Field Party," in the "Past Is Present" section, Anthropology Newsletter, 28, No.8, 4. November, 1987 (Box 124, Folder 35)
  - Reviews, R1-R8 inclusive 1930-1939 (Box 124, Folder 36)
  - Reviews, R9-R18 inclusive 1940-1944 (Box 124, Folder 37)
  - Reviews, R19-R29 inclusive 1945-1949 (Box 124, Folder 38)
  - Reviews, R30-R37 1950-1954 (Box 124, Folder 39)
  - Reviews, R38-R54 inclusive 1955-1959 (Box 124, Folder 40)
  - Reviews, R55-R96 1960-1964 (Box 124, Folder 41)
  - Reviews, R97-R102 inclusive 1965-1969 (Box 124, Folder 42)
  - Reviews, R103-R111 inclusive 1970-1974 (Box 124, Folder 43)
  - Reviews, R112-R inclusive 1975 (Box 124, Folder 44)
  - MEO Biography--Biographical Materials (Folder #1) 1935-1994 (Box 124, Folder 45)
  - MEO Biography--Biographical Materials (Folder #2) 1929-1984 (Box 124, Folder 46)
  - MEO Biography--Biographical Materials (Folder #3) 1970-1992 (Box 124, Folder 47)
  - MEO Biography--Biographical Materials (Folder #4) Minutes of meeting of Submcommittee on Training Fellowships, of Committee on Personality in Relation to Culture of Division of Anthropology and Psychology of National Research Council (M.E.O. correspondence with Kelly and Nyce) December 21, 1935 (Box 124, Folder 48)
  - MEO Work in Press 1943-1995 (Box 124, Folder 49)
  - MEO Bibliography--Extra Copies 1936-1977 (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - Certificate and Citation from the University of Buffalo 1948 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - MEO Biography--Master Copy and Annual Report Material 1907-1989 (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - MEO Bibliography--Master Copy (Also Themes Bibliography and South Asia Program Bibliography) 1936-1976 (Box 125, Folder 4)
  - MEO Biography--Comments, Publicity, etc., on MEO Work 1937-1977 (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - MEO Biography--Extra Copies 1907 (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - Morris Opler Award Morris Op in Cultural Anthropology (Univ. of Oklahoma) (Extra Copies) May 10, 1992 (Box 125, Folder 7)
  - Morris E. Opler Nature American Language Laboratory Dedication (Extra Copies) April 30, 1993 (Box 125, Folder 8)
  - "The Territories of the Apache Groups of the American Southwest." (Typescript in 3 parts): Part I: Before American Occupation (23pp.) Part II: At and Immediately After American Occupation (26 pp.) Part III: The Evidence of Modern Investigation (59 pp.) (Report prepared for use in Indian claims.) Unpublished. 1907-1940 (Box 125, Folder 9)
  - "Report on Observations at the Mescalero Reservation." (Report for Office of Indian Affairs, mimeographed for distribution by this office in September, 1936.) (Mimeographed, 23 pp.) Now published in M.E.O. article: "Applied Anthropology and the Apache," Papers in Anthropology (Univ. of Oklahoma), 16, No.2, 1-77. (A119) 1936 and Fall, 1975 (Box 125, Folder 10)
  - "An Analysis of Mescalero and Chiricahua Apache Social Organization in the Light of Their Systems of Relationship" (Ph.D. dissertation, University of Chicago, 1933. Typescript, 112pp., reproduced copy--in black binder) In this folder is a part of the dissertation (19 pp.), printed as a private edition, distributed by the University of Chicago Libraries, 1936. 1933 and 1936 (Box 125, Folder 11)
  - "The Jicarilla Apache Indians and Their Territories." (Typescript, 28 pp.) (Report prepared for use in Indian claims for Stanford Research Institute, Menlo Park, Calif.) Unpublished. 1846 (Box 125, Folder 12)
  - "Anthropology and Indian Administration." (Outline of a course given at Sequoyah Indian School, summer, 1937.) (Mimeographed, 3 pp.) Unpublished. Summer, 1937 (Box 125, Folder 13)
  - "Indian Organization and Related Problems on the San Carlos Reservation." (Report for Office of Indian Affairs in August, 1936.) (Typescript, 19 pp.) Now published in M.E.O. article: "Applied Anthropology and the Apache," Papers in Anthropology (Univ. of Oklahoma), 16, No.2 (Fall, 1975), 1-77. (A119) August, 1936 and Fall, 1975 (Box 125, Folder 14)
  - "Report on the Fort Apache Indians of Arizona" (Report for Office of Indian Affairs, mimeographed for distribution by this office in 1936.) (Mimeographed, 37 pp.) Now published in M.E.O. article: "Applied Anthropology and the Apache," Papers in Anthropology (Univ. of Oklahoma), 16, No.2 (Fall, 1975), 1-77 (A119) 1936 and Fall, 1975 (Box 125, Folder 15)
  - "Report of Meeting Feb. 8, 1937, with Fort Sill Apaches." (7 pp.) 1937 (Box 125, Folder 16)
  - M.E.O. Correspondence with Collier (1937) and Beatty (1944). 1937 and 1944 (Box 125, Folder 17)
  - Confidential Memorandum re conditions on the Jicarilla Apache reservation, submitted to John Collier, Commissioner of Indian Affairs, with covering letter dated July 10, 1936. 26 pp. (xeroxed copy) July 10, 1936 (Box 125, Folder 18)
  - "Background Material for Film Documentary on the Removal of the Chiricahua Apache from the West." Prepared for Station KENW-TV, Eastern New Mexico University, Portales, New Mexico 88130. (Keith Kolb, Production Director). 1982 (Box 125, Folder 19)
  - "Serious Thoughts about Laughter." (For office of Indian Affairs, prepared for a Gov't. pamphlet, 1936.) (Typescript, 4 pp.) 1936 (Box 125, Folder 20)
  - Brief of Japanese American Citizens League in the Supreme Court of the United States (October term, 1944). (No. 22--Korematsu case re detention.) Unpublished. Reprinted as "The Case for the Nisei" by the Japanese American Citizens League. 1944 (Box 125, Folder 21)
  - Brief of Japanese American Citizens League in the United States Circuit States Circuit Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit (No. 10, 299-- Citizenship case). Unpublished. 1943 (Box 125, Folder 22)
  - "India Today." (Typescript, 9pp.). Unpublished. (Box 125, Folder 23)
  - "The Pattern of Spirit Possession in a Village of Northern India." (Typescript, carbon, 8pp.) Unpublished. 1947-1948 (Box 125, Folder 24)
  - "Some Background Factors Pertinent to Population Control Efforts in Rural India." (Later revised for Haring Festschrift) 1958 (Box 125, Folder 25)
  - Foreword prepared for book on suicide in comparative cultures by Elna Smith Melvin (Mrs. Bruce L. Melvin). (Typescript, 4pp.) The book was not published. 1947 (Box 125, Folder 26)
  - "Education and the Development of Social Attitudes in a Preliterate and in a Modern Community." (A paper read before Symposium on Environmental Influences on Child Development, October 30, 1936, in Washington, D.C., under the auspices of the Society for Research in Child Development.) (Typescript, 11pp.). Unpublished. October 30, 1936 (Box 125, Folder 27)
  - "Education and Social Science." (Typescript, 12pp.). Unpublished. 1947 (Box 125, Folder 28)
  - "Survey of the Grosse Pointe Country Day School and the Detroit University School, Grosse Pointe, Michigan, 17-21 February 1948." (With P.J. Rulon, E.W. Flinton, L.J. Barry, F.G. Watson, and F.A. Zehrer). Unpublished. 1948 (Box 125, Folder 29)
  - "Problems concerning Official and Popular Participation in Development Projects" (Prepared for UNESCO conference on Social Aspects of Technical Assistance Programmes for Economic Development). March, 1953. Unpublished. 1953 (Box 125, Folder 30)
  - "Development of Pre-Industrial Areas: Theory, Research, and Policy." (Columbia University, University Seminar 415-416, Meeting of April 17, 1956.) Unpublished. 1956 (Box 125, Folder 31)
  - Review of: Social Economy of a Polyandrous People by R.N. Saksena. Agra: Agra University Press. Pp. vii and 120. (Sent to American Journal of Sociology on December 26, 1956. Cannot find that it was published.) 1956 (Box 125, Folder 32)
  - "Loyalty" Paper by MEO- Xerox Copies (3 MEO file copies and 1 working Copy) 1945 (Box 125, Folder 33)
  - "Loyalty" Paper by M.E.O.- Xerox Copy for Frank Chuman 1943 (Box 125, Folder 34)
  - "Loyalty" Paper by MEO 2nd (Final) Draft (Hold-Rough, Edited Copy) 1943-1982 (Box 127, Folder 35)
  - "Loyalty Paper" by MEO- Typescript and Correspondence 1985 (Box 125, Folder 36)
  - "Report on the History and Contemporary State of Aspects of Creek Social Organization and Government." (Report for Office of Indian Affairs, mimeographed for distribution by this office in July, 1937.) (Mimeographed, 43pp.) Now published in M.E.O. monograph: The Creek Indian Towns of Oklahoma in 1937. Papers in Anthropology (Univ. of Oklahoma), 13, No.1 (Spring, 1972), 1-116 (whole issue) (B50) 1937 (Box 125, Folder 37)
  - "Report on Meeting with Creek Indians near Hana, Oklahoma." (Report for Office of Indian Affairs.) (Typescript, 6pp.) Now unpublished in M.E.O. monograph: The Creek Indian Towns of Oklahoma in 1937. Papers in Anthropology (Univ. of Oklahoma), 13, No.1 (Spring, 1972), 1-116 (whole issue) (B50) 1937 (Box 125, Folder 38)
  - "Report of Meeting Held with Members of a Creek Town near Wetumka, Oklahoma, March 11." (Report for Office of Indian Affairs, 1937.) (Typescript, 10pp.) Now published in M.E.O. mongraph: The Creek Indian Towns of Oklahoma in 1937. Papers in Anthropology (Univ. of Oklahoma), 13, No.1 (Spring, 1972), 1-116 (whole issue) (B50) 1972 (Box 125, Folder 39)
  - "Memorandum in Regard to Creek Towns." (Report for Office of Indian Affairs, 1937.) (Typescript, 7pp.) Now published in M.E.O. monograph: The Creek Indian Towns of Oklahoma in 1937. Papers in Anthropology (Univ. of Oklahoma), 13, No.1 (Spring, 1972), 1-116 (whole issue) (B50) 1937 and 1972 (Box 125, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous Unpublished Materials 1947 (Box 125, Folder 41)
  - Apache Odyssey- Publication 1968-1971 (Box 125, Folder 42)
  - The Lipan and Mescalero Apaches in Texas (Univ. of Oklahoma Press) 1971 (Box 125, Folder 43)
  - Lipan Ethnology- Publication 1969-1971 (Box 125, Folder 44)
  - Cultural Anth. Book- Allyn and Bacon Publication 1965-1971 (Box 125, Folder 45)
  - Theory Book-Harper Publication 1961 (Box 125, Folder 46)
  - MEO Theoretical Essays- Publication 1963-1965 (Box 125, Folder 47)
  - Arail- Publication (Spindler) 1958 (Box 125, Folder 48)
  - Dobyns, Henry. "Historical Perspective" Newberry Library 1989 (Box 125, Folder 49)
  - "Economic Realities, Factionalism, and the American Indian" Akwesashe Notes 1982 (Box 125, Folder 50)
  - Book Reviews: Oglala Women: Myth, Ritual and Reality by Marla Powers 1988 (Box 125, Folder 51)
  - Biolsi, Thomas "The American Indian and the Problem of Culture" American Indian Quarterly 1989 (Box 125, Folder 52)
  - Hemphill, Joseph A. "The Development of Tribal Gov't. on the Wind River Indian Res. M.S. (Box 125, Folder 53)
  - Straus, Anne Sawyier "Being Human in The Cheyenne Way" 1976 (Box 125, Folder 54)
  - Leacock, Eleanor "Some Aspects of the Philosophy of the Cheyenne and Arapano Indians" (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Goddard, Ives. "Sketch of Arapaho Linguistic History" MS 1965 (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - Gross, Feliks "Language and Value Changes Among the Arapaho" 1951 (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Weist, Katherine Morrett "The Northern Cheyennes: Diversity in a Loosely Structured Society" 1958 and 1962 (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - A Problem and a Point of Departure (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - Golla, Susan "History and Social Structure Among the Indians of Western Vancouver Island 1986 (Box 126, Folder 6)
  - Johnson, Thomas Hoevet "The Enos Family and Wind River Shoshone Society: A Historical Analysis" 1965,1969 and 1975 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Copies of MEO articles for Western History. [Also update bibliography first] 1987 (Box 126, Folder 8)
  - Songs-Social Dances, English Translations of 68-102 (Box 126, Folder 9)
  - Xerox Copies fo Social Dance Songs 68-102 (Box 126, Folder 10)
  - Songs Translations 27-67 (Box 126, Folder 11)
  - Gahe Song, 27-67 Xerox Copy (Box 126, Folder 12)
  - Ludtke, Jean Edwards "The Mashpee Wampanoags: A Case of Ethnic Resurrection" 1974 (Box 126, Folder 13)
  - Girl's Puberty Rite, Tipi Pole Song (Box 126, Folder 14)
  - English Translation- Puberty Rite Song 1-26 (Box 126, Folder 15)
  - Norman Items 1994 (Box 126, Folder 16)
  - War and Victory Songs Translations-2nd Copy English 103-107 (Box 126, Folder 17)
  - Translation- War and Victory 103-107, Xerox Copy # 1 (Box 126, Folder 18)
  - Moccasin Game Song, 108-110 (Box 126, Folder 19)
  - Moccasin Game Song, 108-110, Xerox Copy # 1 (Box 126, Folder 20)
  - Songs-Ceremonial Music, English Translation 2nd Copy, 111-124 (Box 126, Folder 21)
  - Songs-Ceremonial Music, English Translation, 111-124, Xerox Copy # 1 (Box 126, Folder 22)
  - Translation-Social Dances 68-102, Xerox Copy # 2 (Box 126, Folder 23)
  - Song Texts, Girls Puberty 1-26, 2nd Copy in Apache (Box 126, Folder 24)
  - Cornell University Letter 1990 (Box 126, Folder 25)
  - Correspodence- Luckert Texts-symbols (Box 126, Folder 26)
  - LRO- To Do (Box 126, Folder 27)
  - Gahe Songs-Texts-2nd Copy 27-67 (Box 126, Folder 28)
  - Song Texts-2nd Copy, Social Dances, 68-102 (Box 126, Folder 29)
  - War and Victory Dance Songs, 103-107, carbon song texts-2nd copies (Box 126, Folder 30)
  - Moccasin Game-108-110, Song Texts-2nd Copy-Carbon (Box 126, Folder 31)
  - Song Ceremonial Misc. 111-124, Texts 2nd Copy carbon (Box 126, Folder 32)
  - Moccasin Game-108-110 Texts 1st Copy (Box 126, Folder 33)
  - Ceremonial Songs 111-124, Texts 1st Copies (Box 126, Folder 34)
  - MEO Items to be sent Also Neil Goodwin List 1993 (Box 126, Folder 35)
  - Trans-War and Victory 103-107, Xerox Copy # 2 (Box 126, Folder 36)
  - McClellan (Type Cards) 1956-1981 (Box 126, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence Apacheau Items, 1980-1984 (Box 126, Folder 38)
  - trans.-Ceremonial Misc. 111-124, Xerox Copy # 2 (Box 126, Folder 39)
  - Trans. Gahe, 27-67, Xerox Copy # 2 (Box 126, Folder 40)
  - Apache Texts, Girls Puberty, 1-26, 1st Copy Apache (Box 126, Folder 41)
  - trans.-Puberty Rite-1-26, Xerox Copy # 2 1907-1997 (Box 126, Folder 42)
  - Trans.-Moccasin Game 108-110 Xerox and Copy # 2 (Box 126, Folder 43)
  - Articles about Bob Smith from Cornell Chronicle 1992-1993 (Box 126, Folder 44)
  - Song Texts-Gahe-1st Copy, 27-67 (Box 126, Folder 45)
  - Social Dances 68-102 (Box 126, Folder 46)
  - War and Victory Dance Texts 1st Copy 103-107 (Box 126, Folder 47)
  - Senior Citizen Information 1994 (Box 126, Folder 48)
  - Allan Houser 1994 (Box 126, Folder 49)
  - MEO Review- To Type 1983-1989 (Box 126, Folder 50)
  - To Do (Box 126, Folder 51)
  - University of Oklahoma, Indiana University, and Meschalero-Chiricahua Songs, Misc. (Box 126, Folder 52)
  - Corrected Galleys of Apache, Song Texts in Apache Xerox Copy (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Corrected Galleys of Apache Song Texts (in Apache) 1st Copy 1-124 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - "India." (Legal-sized typescript, 130pp.). Unpublished. (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Court Cases 1861-1977 (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - Court Cases 1831-1977 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Court Cases 1975-1977 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Mashpee Tribe v. New Seabury Corporation April 25,1977 (Box 127, Folder 7)
  - Award Plaque on Morris E. Opler (Box 127, Folder 8)
  - Picture of Mr. Morris E. Opler and Mrs. Opler (Box 127, Folder 9)
  - (Large grey metal box) Morris E. Opler Addresses (Box 127, Folder 10)
  - (smaller grey metal box) Morris E. Opler: Biography Unpublished Material Themes Bibliography (Box 127, Folder 11)
  - (smaller grey metal box) Morris E. Opler: Bibliography (Box 127, Folder 12)
  - Wooden Award, Morris Opler, Fellow Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences 1956-1957 (Box 127, Folder 13)
  - Morris and Lucille Opler Photo Album pictures taken by Peter and Monika Krawer 1980's (Box 127, Folder 14)
  - 2 VHS tapes (Box 127, Folder 15)
  - Color Slides of India, 120-180 slides (Box 127, Folder 16)
  - Book, Ledger, Harriet E. Peterson 1956-1978 (Box 127, Folder 17)
  - The University of Oklahoma Library 1724 (Box 127, Folder 18)
  - Mrs. Lucille R. Opler, Photograph 1997 (Box 127, Folder 19)
  - Mrs. Lucille R. Opler, Important Genealogical Information 1997 (Box 127, Folder 20)
  - Mrs. Lucille Ritter Opler and/or Family 1997 (Box 127, Folder 21)
  - Photography Of Mr. Morris E. Opler and Mrs. Lucille Ritter Opler (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - Diplomas, etc. (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - Varma, Baidya Nath A New Survey of the Social Sciences 1962 (Box 132)
  - Nathonson, Jerome Science for Democracy 1946 (Box 132)
  - Hulett, J.E. Jr., Stagner, Ross Problems in Social Psychology 1952 (Box 132)
  - Opler, Morris E. Social Aspects of Technical Assistance in Operation 1954 (Box 132)
  - Meister, Albert, editor Community Development 1960 (Box 132)
  - Karr Publication Service World Affairs Are Your Affairs 1952 (Box 132)
  - University of Chicago Press The American Journal of Sociology Nov. 1945 (Box 132)
  - U. S. Declaration of Independence (printed copy) 7/4/1776 (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Declaration of Rights (printed copy) 6/12/1776 (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Navajo paintings and photographs (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - Apache photographs (Box 133, Folder 3)
  - Jicarilla and Navajo paintings (Box 133, Folder 4)
  - Jicarilla Girl's Puberty Rite (Paintings) (Box 133, Folder 5)
  - Jicarilla Relay Race (Paintings) (Box 133, Folder 6)
  - Jicarilla Holiness Rite (Paintings) (Box 133, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified ceremony (Paintings) (Box 133, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified paintings (Box 133, Folder 9)
  - Photo Album A: Indian [U.S.] Pictures and Manzanar 1935-1945 (Box 143)
  - Photo Album B: U.S. 1932-1935 (Box 143)
  - Photo Album: U.S. 1929-1931 (Box 143)
  - Roll film negatives: Apache Mat. Cult. negatives/Possible negatives for an Apache Life-Way n.d. (Box 143)
- Series IX. Oversize Material
  - Maps- Manzanar (Map-case AA-16)
  - 'Combinations of Masks' (Map-case AA-16)
  - Maps- Indian Lands and Reservations (Map-case AA-16)
  - Maps- General Apache (Map-case AA-16)
  - Maps- Lipan Apache (Map-case AA-16)
  - Maps- Texas, Chisholm Trail (Map-case AA-16)
  - Maps- Indian Reservation (Map-case AA-16)
  - Maps- Senapur (Map-case AA-16)
  - Misc. Building Plans- Opler (Box 118)
  - Maps- U.S. (Map-case S18, Folder 1)
  - Maps- Mexico (Map-case S18, Folder 1)
  - Maps- New Mexico (Map-case S18, Folder 1)
  - Maps- Indian Reservations in U.S. (Map-case S18, Folder 1)
  - Maps- Mescalero (Map-case S18, Folder 1)
  - North American Indian Languages (Map-case S18, Folder 2)
  - Maps- Western Apache (mostly AZ) (Map-case S18, Folder 2)
  - Maps- U.S., 1857 (Map-case S18, Folder 2)
  - Misc. hand-drawn maps of Indian towns and states (Box 119)